here's an amazing diagram due to Rex woo
this is a 3x2 rectangle where we've
inscribed a triangle because these two
highlighted triangles are similar the
inscribed triangle is a right triangle
that happens to be isosceles so these
other two angles are pi over four we can
compute this Arc Length of pi over four
by using these two triangles here which
have angle measurements of arc tangent
one over two and arctangent one over
three using the rectangular diagram we
can compute the other pi over 4 angle as
the difference of the angles pictured in
these two triangles which are arc
tangent of three and arc tangent of one
half respectively using the diagram we
can compute that same pi over 4 angle
using the difference of the angles in
these two triangles which are arc
tangent of two and arctangent of 1 3
respectively we can also compute the
upper right pi over 2 angle as the sum
of the angles in these three picture
triangles so we get that pi over two is
arc tangent one plus arctangent a half
plus arctangent a third and finally we
can compute this Pi angle as the sum of
the angles in these three triangles so
we get that Pi is arctangent of one plus
arc tangent of two plus arctangent of
three this diagram has given us five
formulas for pi